scalable vector graphics or svg is an image format that's like html for
可缩放矢量图形或 svg 是一种图像格式，类似于用于 2d 图形的 html，
2d graphics they differ from raster images like png or jpeg
它们与使用微小像素网格来创建图像的光栅图像（如 png 或 jpeg）不同
that use a grid of tiny pixels to create an image and as you zoom in the pixels
，并且当您放大像素时，像素
become larger making the image grainy in contrast a vector image can be scaled to
会变大，从而使图像具有颗粒感 矢量图像可以缩放到
any size without losing its resolution because instead of fixed pixels its
任何大小而不会丢失其分辨率，因为它的外观不是基于固定像素，而是
appearance is based on geometry you can create svgs with tools like
基于几何图形，您可以使用 figma 或 illustrator 等工具创建 svg，
figma or illustrator or by writing the code directly which is
或者直接编写代码，这
easier than you might think and opens the door to animation and
比您想象的要容易并打开 动画和
interactivity create one by opening an svg tag
交互性的门通过打开一个 svg 标签来创建一个，
then define a coordinate system with the view box attribute
然后定义一个带有 view box 属性的坐标系，
that gives us a frame with a width and height of 100 units on which we can draw
它为我们提供了一个宽度和高度为 100 单位的框架，我们可以在其上绘制
graphics draw basic shapes by adding elements like rectangle
图形通过添加矩形圆等元素来绘制基本形状
circle and polygon position the rectangle by defining its x-y value
和多边形通过在视图框上定义其 x-y 值来定位矩形，
on the view box then give it a size which can take values that are either
然后给它一个可以采用
explicit or responsive we can change the color of the shape by
显式或响应值的大小我们可以通过定义它的填充来改变形状的颜色，
defining its fill or define an outline with the stroke attribute and if our
或者用 stroke 属性定义一个轮廓，如果我们的
styling gets too complex we can extract everything into a separate css
样式变得太复杂，我们可以通过对它应用一个类来将所有内容提取到一个单独的 css
stylesheet by applying a class to it just like any
样式表中，就像
html element we have the full power of css at our
我们拥有的任何 html 元素一样 css 的全部功能
fingertips which means we can react to events on the shapes and then change
触手可及，这意味着我们可以对形状上的事件做出反应，然后相应地更改
their styling or animation accordingly but most graphics are more than just
它们的样式或动画，但大多数图形不仅仅是
basic shapes they contain complex artwork with all kinds of twists and
基本形状，它们包含复杂的艺术作品和各种
turns and that's where the path element comes in
曲折，这就是 路径元素
the shape of a path is determined by one attribute d
以路径的形状出现 路径由一个属性 d
for draw coding a path is like controlling the tip of a pen with a
用于绘制 编码路径就像用一系列命令控制笔尖
series of commands the most basic command is m for move
最基本的命令是 m 移动
which will move the pen tip to an x y coordinate
，它将笔尖移动到 x y
an uppercase letter means move relative to the view box and lowercase means
坐标大写字母表示相对于视图框移动，小写表示
move relative to the last point in the path but move doesn't actually draw
相对于路径中的最后一个点移动，但移动实际上并没有绘制
anything to put the pen tip down on the paper and
任何东西来放置笔尖 d 自己在纸上并
draw something use the l command it works exactly like move but draws a
使用 l 命令绘制一些东西，它的工作原理与 move 完全一样，但是绘制
line that can be styled straight lines are cool but what if we
一条可以设置为直线样式的线很酷，但是如果我们
wanted to add a curve like we would with the handles in illustrator
想添加一条曲线，就像我们在 illustrator 中使用手柄
create bezier curves with the c and q commands define the position of two
创建贝塞尔曲线一样 c 和 q命令定义两个控制点的位置，
control points then the x and y coordinates where the
然后定义曲线应该结束的 x 和 y 坐标，
curve should end then svg will automatically calculate a smooth curve
然后 svg 将自动为您计算任意比例的平滑曲线
for you at any scale this has been scalable
vector graphics in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos like this
如果您想查看更多，这已在 100 秒内可缩放矢量图形像这样的短视频
hit the like button and subscribe thanks for watching and i will see you
点击喜欢按钮并订阅感谢观看，我会在下一个看到你
in the next one